PERSONAL SUMMARY

Visionary Creative Operations Manager and curious storyteller with over 25 years of technical video knowledge, 15 years of project management & process development, 12 years leading creative production teams, and a knack for finding patterns and solutions. I believe in cultivating a culture of trust through awareness, open communication, and empowerment. My philosophy is that positive accountability and honest expectations lead to strong team relationships and innovative collaboration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oklahoma Contemporary Oklahoma City, OK 2022-present Visitor Experience // Gallery Guide

NicholiNoah.com LLC Oklahoma City, OK 2018-present AR/VR Creative Education and Content Production

- Created Open Source VR Education tools with devs from Microsoft and Google
- AR/VR Team Collaboration, Logistics, and Creative Content Production
- Vast knowledge of XR/MR and spatial media systems, processes, and culture
- Generative Al & LLM tools for research, content production, and collaboration

University of Central Oklahoma Video Studio Manager (eLearning)

Edmond, OK 2017-2018

- Lead, assigned & scheduled three member eLearning studio production team
- Integrated project planning and collaboration software template and training
- Produced weekly status reports including forecast of upcoming productions
- Developed 360° augmented reality Construction Management program

Daniel Brian AdvertisingVideo Editor // Studio Operations Manager

- Streamlined interdepartmental communication with kick-off task assignments
- Hired, trained, and mentored junior video editor and contributing creatives
- Ensured quality control, final delivery, & systematic archival of all audio/video
- Actively contributed to Creative Team projects (brainstorms, pitches, solutions)
- Conserved \$30k by restructuring outdated broadcast media delivery system

University of Central Oklahoma Edmond, OK 2015-2011 Operations Manager, University Video Services

- Founded and operated video services department with three-member team
- Technical Directed and equipment managed 100+live multicamera productions
- Client-focused business model raised \$25k toward UCO rebranding innitiative
- Mentored student creatives for three semesters of Video Magazine Production

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Manager Development Program

University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, OK 2019

BA Communication & Professional Media

University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, OK 2002

Advanced Storytelling Workshop

National Press Photographers Association | Austin, TX 2012

News Video Workshop

National Press Photographers Association | Norman, OK 2010

CHARACTERISTICS

- Team-Serving Leader
- Collaborative Coach
- Diverse Communicator
- Proactive Thinker
- Accomplishment Driven
- Quality Assurance

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & TOOLSETS

• Project Management

• Generative AI & LLM

(Wrike, Trello, Jira, Asana, Gantt Chart) (OpenAl, Pica, Hugging Face, Mistral)

Multimedia Production

(Audio/Video, Design, Animation)

Team Collaboration

(Microsoft Teams, Teamwork, GitHub)

Adobe Creative Cloud

(Premiere, AE, Illustrator, Photoshop)

HONORS & AWARDS

- deadCenter Film Festival official selection (2020: Virtual Reality)
- NATAS Upper Midwest Regional EMMY®

(2014: Campaign)

NATAS Ohio Valley Regional EMMY®

(2013: Commercial)

INTERESTS & HOBBIES







Travel

Mindfulness

XR Film